Christopher Ashby

Cyber Attack Detection and Threat Response Leader

(518) 577-8597

ashbyc@mac.com

https://ashbyca.com

PGP: 3679D138AE307F2A

Summary

Highly experienced pragmatic executive with demonstrated success architecting, improving, and managing cyber security related services. Constant willingness to align and respond to the continuous evolving threat landscape, business needs, and regulatory requirements. Confident in leading diverse teams dedicated to assessing business risks, defining appropriate mitigation, managing enterprise execution, and enhancing operational efficiency. A trusted advisor and strategic problem solver taking a collaborative approach on resolving complex security problems that enable businesses to achieve their outcomes successfully across all levels of the organization.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Security Engineer, Global Security Solutions

Alexion Pharmaceuticals, New Haven, CT, 2019-Present

Created and led the incident response, threat hunting, purple team, and cyber hygiene programs across the organization. Acted as a threat reduction subject matter expert in various working groups to continuously drive down risk and increase resiliency across the organization. Other key responsibilities included:

- Collaboratively worked across the IT enterprise to resolve identified issues including configuration weaknesses and other software weaknesses.
- Worked closely with executives on mitigation strategies to ensure the appropriate levels of risk were maintained.
- Implemented continuous process improvements in cybersecurity incident response tactics, techniques, procedures.
- Served as a role model, teacher, mentor for security analysts, and IT workforce who weren't well versed in cyber risk or security operations.

Cyber Intel Watch Commander

Digitalware, New York, NY, 2019–2019

Responsibilities included developing the long-term strategy and executing day to day management of a 24x7 Fusion Center environment which included a multifaceted elite team of technology engineers, data scientists, security analysts, and threat researchers serving multiple clients across various verticals including banking, entertainment and, local state governments.

- Conducted daily strategic threat briefings for high profile customers that included in-depth threat-actor assessments, TTPs, and risk reduction remediations.
- Executive level interactions in supporting city agencies C-suite particularly CISO, CSO, CIO, and CTO.

SKILLS

Enterprise Security
Architecture

Purple Team Exercises

Adversarial Emulation

Threat Hunting

Policy and Governance

Project Management

Cloud Computing

Creative Thinking

Security Program Metrics

NIST CSF Framework

Cyber Threat Intelligence

Security Orchestration and Automation

Employee Training and Development

Stakeholder Engagement

Data Privacy

Security Risk Management

Incident Response and Mitigation

Vulnerability Management

Education

Harvard, Cambridge MA Graduate Certificate

2020-2020

Cyber Risk Managemen

Cyber Risk Management in the Information Age

Ithaca College, Ithaca NY

Graduate Certificate 2020-2020

Cyber Security Leadership

Director, Information Security

CBS Corporation, New York, NY, 2013-2018

Developed and managed a global threat intelligence strategy that provided visibility around providing a holistic view of the security landscape across the enterprise.

- Managed and automated the collection of OSINT & Commercial threat feeds producing operational intelligence for remote teams.
- Generated and delivered routine business readiness intelligence providing an early warning of potential threats
- Created and distributed threat metrics, advisories, and daily threat briefings that clearly articulated the security landscape to executives.

Principle IT Security Analyst

GLOBALFOUNDRIES, Malta, NY, 2011-2013

Work as a team lead responsible for US security operations within a semiconductor manufacturing facility. General responsibilities included security operations, architecture, and security solutions design as necessary to support a mission critical global operation.

- Provided technical leadership to the enterprise for the information security programs and team members.
- Maintained, managed, and frequently engaged with third-party relationships.
- Recommended, implemented, and maintained, new and existing security infrastructure including network IPS devices, Firewalls, Proxies, and VPN appliances.
- Continuously assessed threats, risks, and vulnerabilities from emerging security events using various organic and vendor implemented solutions.

Information Security Specialist

The Active Network, Saratoga, NY, 2010-2011

Worked as a cyber security subject matter expert providing support and leadership on various company initiatives including:

- PCI compliance testing for Level1 Merchant Accreditation
- Network Security architecture reviews and audits
- Vulnerability discovery and Penetration testing

Information Security Specialist

SAIC, Albany, NY, 2009-2010

Worked as part of a team of security specialists performing various administrative forensic investigations utilizing open source and commercial toolkits including Helix v3, FTK Pro v2.x, and Sleuth Kit. Worked closely with NY Agency Commissioners on reducing physical security risks to both inmates and correctional officers.

Senior Information Security Specialist

ReserveAmerica, Malta, NY, 2008-2009

Developed and executed various internal white-hat penetration tests against newly interconnected infrastructures and attached hosts ensuring proper mitigating security controls were in place.

Publications

PenTest Regular Magazine Pass-The-Hash Attacks Published April 2013

Article explaining the post exploitation attack techniques used to elevate privileges and/or create new authenticated sessions.

PenTest Extra Magazine Automating Malware Analysis with Cuckoo Published: August 2013

Article on implementing an automated technique to aid in the identification and analysis of suspicious software.

PenTest Regular Magazine Extending Cuckoo Framework Published: November 2013

Article describing some of the advanced features, capabilities, and extensibility of the Cuckoo Platform.

Certifications

Certified Information Systems Security Professional - CISSP

Certified Cloud Security Professional – CCSP

Certified Information Security Manager – CISM

Comptia Security+

ITIL v3

Professional Associations

Ithaca College Board Member

InfraGard Southern CT Member

Operations Security Trust Member

ISC – Southern CT Chapter Member